Abdullah Al Masud

Mobile App Developer (Android & Flutter)



- ♥ Flat-A2, House-5, Road-5, Block-C, Section-6, Mirpur, Dhaka-1216.
- almasud.arm@gmail.com
- ****01737606053
- **○** GitHub □

SUMMARY

I am a Software engineer with experience in the mobile application development industry, I have specialized in creating native Android and Flutter-based mobile applications. My extensive background in these areas enables me to produce high-quality, efficient mobile solutions tailored to meet specific client needs.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science & Engineering

Dhaka International University ☐ 2015 – 2019 | Dhaka, Bangladesh

SKILLS

Language

Java, Kotlin, XML, Dart, Python, PHP, JavaScript, HTML5 & CSS3, Basic Swift.

Library

Jetpack compose, Hilt, Bloc, GetIt, RxDart, Google Map etc.

Development Tools

Android Studio, Visual Studio Code, XCode, Git, Postman, Jira.

Database

MySQL, SQLite, Firebase Realtime & Firestore.

Operating Systems

MacOS, MS Windows, Android, Linux (Ubuntu)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

NybSys Inc. ☑

Software Engineer (Android & Flutter) 09/2021 - present | Dhaka, Bangladesh

Responsibilities/Tasks:

- Android application development
- Flutter application development

XOR Geek □

Mobile Application Engineer 09/2020 - 09/2021 | Dhaka, Bangladesh

Responsibilities/Tasks:

- Android application development
- Flutter application development
- Web application development

PROJECTS

• **Xtreme VPN** □: A mobile app for Android platform where you experience unparalleled online security and freedom with Xtreme VPN, Xtreme VPN stands as a fortress to safeguard your digital presence.

Build tools: Android, Java, Kotlin etc.

• **DrinkWell** □: A mobile app for Android/iOS platform where a Pump operator can register a water ATM card for a user, recharge to the user's water ATM card, daily report etc. through the app.

Build with: Flutter, NFC tag reader etc.

- **Sentra PTT** [2]: A PTT (Push to Talk) mobile app for Android platform that connects your team instantly. Its rich media features, alerts, photos, location sharing, calls & messaging provide this app the greatest power. **Build tools**: Android, Java, etc.
- Hokkaido Classic Golf Club App □: A mobile app for Android platform that dedicated for a Golf Club. a registered member of the club can access and use the app.

 Build tools: Android, Java, etc.
- One-Click Order App □: A mobile app for Android/iOS platform where a registered member by the company can access the app and can order products by using the app. Build tools: Flutter.
- One-Click Order App API & Admin Panel □: A web app that provides the API for the mobile app and manage the products, members and their orders through mobile app.

 Build tools: Laravel.
- **Augmented Learn** □: An educational app for Android platform that helps to teach preschool children with Augmented Reality. **Build tools**: Android, Java.